Amiri Baraka papers 6909686
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series II: Writings, 1958-2009
  - Subseries 1: Non-Fiction, 1966-2009
    - General, 1966-2007
      - "Art and the Political Crisis, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - "Amiri Baraka v Rutgers", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Anthologies, 1999
        - Black Fire, undated
          - "New Introduction", undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
          - Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
          - Table of Contents, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
        - Black Fire 2--Book Proposal, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 15)
        - Confirmation, undated
          - General, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
          - Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
          - MS Drafts, undated
            - Corrected, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 18)
            - Inclusions, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 19)
          - Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
          - Introduction, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
          - Reviews and Listings, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - "Arts Review", undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Autobiography of LeRoi Jones
        - Correspondence and Notes, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 24)
        - Contract--Chicago Review Press, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 25)
        - Drafts, 1984-1997
          - Holograph, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 26-27)
          - Freundlich Edition, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 28)
            - First, 1984; (3 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
            - Photocopy Published Version, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
            - Second, 1984; (4 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 5-8)
          - Lawrence Hill Edition, 1994-1997
            - Chapter 1, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 9)
            - Proofs, 1997; (3 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 10-12)
      - "Baraka Family Minus One at Dutchman ", undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - "The Beginnings: Words as Notes and Beats", 1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Beginning of National Movement--Jihad Production Edition, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - "The Big Sea", 1985 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Bios, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Black Arts Bulletin, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - "The Black Arts Movement", 1994 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - "Black and Latino Unity Statement", 1989 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - "Black Leadership in the 90s and the Politics of Racism", (1990s) (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - "Black Music as a Force for Social Change", undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Black Music Table of Contents (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Black Radical Bibliography, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Black Studies and Public Education,1990 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - "The Blues Aesthetic and the Black Aesthetic,", undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - Blues People Cover Proofs, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - Bushwacked, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - "CFUN Newsletter: Words from Imamu", undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Changes in the Black Liberation Movement, 1980-1989 (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - "The Changing Line in the Organization", 1974 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - The Creation of the New Ark, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - MS Draft with Hand Corrections, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - MS Draft with Hand Corrections, 1970-1971; (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - "Cultural Revolution and the Literary Canon", (1990s) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Daggers & Javelins --Introduction, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "Death to Apartheid!", (1990s) (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Democracy, Self-Determination, Elections and the Black Radical Congress", 1990s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Digging, 1986-2009
      - Correspondence, 1999-2008 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Drafts, 1986-2009
        - Complete, 2009; (4 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 8-11)
        - Individual Essays, 1986-2001; (3 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 12-14)
      - Research Material, 1999-2001 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Duncan Spoke of Dance", 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "The Education Crisis", 1973 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Essence of Reparation, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Essence of Reparations and Somebody Blew Up America Proofs, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Eulogies, 1980-1997
      - Essay MSS, 1980-1997 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - General, 1980-1997 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Anna Lois Jones, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - James Baldwin, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Sheila Bittle, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Expansion of the Reader, 1991-2000 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Five Slave Narratives Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Fuck Reagan", undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Ginsberg Tribute, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Greenwich Village and African-American Music", 1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "Griot/Djali", 1996 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Henry Dumas: Afro-Surreal Expressionist", 1988 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "High Art", undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - History of CAP, 1971-1976 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Home: Social Essays, 1997
      - Ecco Press Edition, 1997
        - Contract and Intro, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 13)
        - Cover, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - "Preface", 1997 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Houston Baker--with Correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Holy Terror Introduction, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Interviews, 1983-2007
      - General, 1983-2004; (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
      - "AB with Allen Ginsberg,", 1990 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - "Artist and Influence Series", 1984 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Chops Jones, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Chris Funkhouser, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Grachan Moncur, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Hamiet Bluiett, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - In Motion Transcripts, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Mark Hillringhouse, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Melhem, D.H., 1990 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - "Miles Interview", undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - New Jersey Historical Society, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - "Jackie McClean", 2006 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - "Jazz and the White Critic, 30 Years Later"--Holograph, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Jesse Jackson, 1984-1998
      - Correspondence, 1984-1990 (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - DNC Material, 1984-1988; (4 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 35-38)
      - Jackson Campaign Material, 1984-1989; (3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
      - "Jesse 88" (Essay), 1988
        - Drafts, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - Playboy Proofs, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Jesse Jackson and Black People--Drafts, 1988-1998
        - General, 1988-1998 (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Third World Press Edits, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - Typescript, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Notes, 1984-1988 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Notebooks, 1984-1988 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Printed Matter, 1984-1989; (3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 12-14)
    - John Coltrane, 2001-2003
      - Cassette, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Essays, 2003
        - General, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
        - "John Coltrane: Where Does Art Come From?", undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
        - "Late Trane", 2001-2003 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Research Material, 1969-1997; (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 19-20)
    - Kimako Baraka Funeral, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Lanie Poo", undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Larry Neal, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Last Poets on a Mission--Foreword, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Liner Notes, 1996-2004
      - Albert Ayler, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Andrew Cyrille Trio, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Doctor E. Pelikan Chalto, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Hugh Ragin, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Ravi Coltrane, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Malcolm X, 1988-2001 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Malcolm X Writer's Workshop, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Manning Marable,", undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Max Roach Book, 1983-1997
      - MS, 1983-1997; (4 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 12-15)
      - Notes, 1988-1995; (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
      - Notebooks, 1995; (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 18-19)
      - Research Material, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - "May Day Insert", undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Miles Davis, 1985-1997 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "Miles Interview" Notebook, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - "Monk and Train", 2005 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - The Music, 1986
      - Copyeditor's Questions, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Drafts, 1986; (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 27-29)
      - Uncorrected Proofs, undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Music Reviews, 1998-2000 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - National Black Arts Festival, 1994-1996 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - NEA Theatre Residency Program Application, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "The Negro", undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Negrossity", undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - The New Ark's A Moverin: Sequences of Live Music, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Newark Influence on American Music", 1999-2004 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Newark, My Newark", 1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "New York Art Quintet", 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Nina Returns", 1986 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Northern Iowa Slave Story and Poetry", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Notes, 1978-1998
      - General, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - "The Big Sea", undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - "Black Bolshevik", 1978 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - "Black Boy", undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - "Cultural Revolution", undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - "Haiti", undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - History of Capitalism, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - "The Oral Tradition", undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - "Petals of Blood", undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Ras Baraka, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - "Sidney B's", undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - "On Accepting Feroni Prize,", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "On Patriotism", (1980s) (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - "An Organization of Young Men,"1961 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - "An Open Letter to the Black Nation", 1991 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - "Petty Bourgeois Totalitarianism and the Newark School Board Elections", undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - "PFLAG It's Called", (2000s) (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - "Poetry Journal Collective Project", undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - "The Poetry of Urgent Necessity", 1986 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - "The Position of the Congress of African People", 1974 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Presentation for Percy Sulton, (1980s) (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - "Proposed 'Arts Journal & Review'", undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Radio Transcripts, 1976-1987
      - "Peter Kemper/Wolfgang Mohrhenn", undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
      - WNJR, 1976-1987; (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 35-36)
    - "A Raisin in the Sun 's Enduring Passion"--Photocopy, undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - RAZOR, 1994-2004
      - Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box 20, Folder 38)
      - Drafts, 1994-2004; (4 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 39-42)
      - Organizational Material, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 43)
      - Pamphlets, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 44)
      - RAZOR History--Holograph, undated (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - "Recent Black Literature: The Political Dimensions", (1980s) (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - "Reorganization of National Black Assembly", (1990s) (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Response to Nat Hentoff, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - The Retrograde Trend", undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Reviews, 1999-2000
      - The Great Whirl of Exile, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 50)
      - Slo Dance, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - "Revolutionary Art", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - "Revolutionary Democratic Art from the Cultural Commonwealth of Afro America" from Souls Grown Deep, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - "Revolutionaries Oppose Terrorism", undated (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - "Rhythm", undated (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - "Rosa Parks", undated (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Sam Cornish Blurb, undated (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - Sarah Vaughn Tribute, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 58)
    - "Second Answer to Houston CAP", 1975 (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - "Self Determination is the First Step in the Struggle for Democracy and Socialism", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - "Singers and the Music", 1998 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "Social Change and Poetic Tradition", 1997 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Some Newark Secrets: One-Eyed Jacks, Brothers, and Others", 2000 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Speeches, Lectures, and Talks, 1979-2005
      - General, 1979-2000 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "Address to Asian American Student Organization, Northwestern University,", 2005 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "League of Revolutionary Struggle (M-L),", 1980 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - "National Black United Front", 1980 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "Revolutionary Art", 1994 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "The State of Black America", 2000 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Statement from an African American Artist to the US Supreme Court", 1989 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Stop Killer Cops,", 1992 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Strategy and Tactics of a Pan-African Nationalist Party"--Jihad Pamphlet, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - SUNY Grant Proposal, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Tom Feelings: A People's Artist", (1970s) (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "Unity and Struggle": History of the Revolutionary Communist League (M-L-M)--Galleys, 1980 (Box 147)
    - Venezuela, 2004-2007; (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - "Vincent Has Booked,", 2003 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Vincent the Hip", 2004 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - What Is to Be Done Here. The US, the end of the 20th c. by us?", undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "What Role for the Black Liberation Movement", undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "What's New?: Charlie Braxton,", 1988 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "When Miles Split!", 1991 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Whitney Houston Profile--Playboy, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "Why Our Grieving is Celebration", 2003 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "Wilbur Morris Tribute Celebration", 2002 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "Zora", 1999 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 2: Poetry, 1966-2007
    This series contains holograph, typescript, and computer print drafts of Baraka's published and unpublished poetry and poetry collections, including individual poems from and full drafts of the volumes Funk Lore, Hard Facts, The Selected Poetry of Amiri Baraka/LeRoi Jones, Transbluesency, and Wise, Why's, Y's, as well as a published copy of the Jihad Press edition of Black Art from 1966. Also contained herein is much of Baraka's later, largely unpublished mixed-media poetry. The bulk of the individual poems in this series are grouped alphabetically by title and, additionally, chronologically, while materials relating to poetry collections or with multiple drafts and other attendant materials have been arranged individually.
    - 5 Bop Trees, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - 5 Bop Trees, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Allah Mean Everything, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Alphabetical By Title, 1968-2007
      - A, 1973-2002; (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
      - B, 1970-2002; (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
      - C, 1979-2002; (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
      - D, 1975-2002 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - E, 1980-2004 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - F, 1977-2004 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - G, 1989-1998 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - H, 1967-2004 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - I, 1968-2004 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - J, 1978-2003 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - K, 1985-1995 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - L, 1975-2003 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - M, 1971-2007; (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
      - N, 1982-2003 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - O, 1986-1998 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - P, 1970-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
      - Q, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - R, 1977-2004 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - S, 1969-2004; (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
      - T, 1982-2003 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - U, 1968-2000s (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - V, (1988) (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - W, 1978-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
      - X, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Y, 1970-2002 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Z, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Untitled, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 17-19)
    - Anthology Proofs, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - "Ba-ra-ka,", undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Black Art--Jihad Version, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Black Magic--Proofs, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - "Black People Meet Puppet Man", 1969 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Blood Rites,", 1970s (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Book of Monk, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Booklet, Untitled, 1997-2000 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - By Date, (1960s)-2007
      - "60s, 70s,", 1965-1979 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - "70s and 80s", 1970-1989 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - 1970s 1970-1979 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - 1980s 1980-1989 (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - 1990s 1990-1999 (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - 2000s 2000-2007 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Callallo--Selections--Proofs, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - "Caution, A Disco Near You Wails Death Funk,", undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - "Chant"/"Black Power Chant,", undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - "Corduroy Wings", 2003 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - "Dialectics", undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - "Digging Poetry", undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - "Duke Book", undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - For Bob Thompson, undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Funk Lore, 1989-1999
      - Drafts, 1989-1999; (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 34-35)
      - Proofs, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - "Griot", 1980 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Hard Facts, 1975
      - Congress of Afrikan People Edition, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Photocopies, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - "Holographs", 1987-1994; (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
    - "In the Tradition, 1980-1983
      - Drafts and Performance Notes, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Orders, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - "It's Nation Time" Recording Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Journal Galleys, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - "Jungle Jim Flunks His Screen Test", undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - "Junkies Are Full of (SHHH…), 1969-1975 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - "Low Coup Matrix,", 1998 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Malcolm X, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Mixed Media, 1996-2004 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Mixed Media, undated (Box 147)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - "Our Flesh of Flames" Callaloo, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Photocopies with Performance Notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - "Phrenology,", 2001 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - "A Poem of Destiny", 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Poetry for the Advanced, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Preface to a Twenty Volume Suicide Note Photocopies, undated (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Printed Materials, 1970-2003 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - "Rockgroup", undated (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - "Spacepoem for Four Jones", undated (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Selected Poetry of Amiri Baraka/LeRoi Jones, 1979; (3 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 19-21)
    - "To Raise the Roof", with David Murray and Steve McCall, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Transbluesency, 1995-1996
      - Introduction and Correspondence, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Press Release, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Translations of AB, undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - "Un Poco Low Coup,", 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - "Weimar II", undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Wise, Why's, Y's, 1985-1997
      - "MS Draft and Photocopies,", undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Proofs, 1997; (4 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 29-32)
      - Early Drafts, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 42)
      - Drafts, 1986; (3 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 43-45)
      - Proofs, with Hand Corrections, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - "When We'll Worship Jesus", undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Subseries 3: Plays and Performances, 1966-2009
    Covering materials from Baraka's career as a playwright, this series includes the drafts, correspondence, compositional and staging notes, photos, and published material relating to both scripts and productions of individual plays. Of particular note, in terms of scope, are folders with items relating to Baraka's plays Dutchman, The Life and Life of Bumpy Johnson, Portrait of the Lion, Primitive World, Song, and Money, as well as a 1979 production of What was the Relationship of the Lone Ranger to the Means of Production? The items in this series are arranged alphabetically by title.
    - General, 1970-2000s; (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - Amiri Baraka: Poetry of the 50s-60s & 70s, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - "Archie, Philly Joe, AB", 1984 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Arm Yrslf or Harm Yrself, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - The Bike Project, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "Billy Harper Project--Some Ideas,", 2006 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - The Birthday, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Black Mass, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Black People Meet Puppet Man, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - A Black Quartet: Four New Black Plays, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Black Theatre USA Table of Contents, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Blue Ark, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Blue Ladies of the Music, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Board of Education: A Skit for Youth, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Boy and Tarzan Appear in a Clearing, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Candace Awards Script, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Car Nazi, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Columbia the Gem of the Ocean, (1970s) (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Dr. King and the Mountain, 1997; (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 19-20)
    - Dr. King and the Mountain, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - DuBois--Untitled, undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Dutchman, 1964-2007
      - Drafts, 1964
        - Adaptation with Duma Ndlovu, undated (Box 26, Folder 22)
        - Typescript, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Performance Photographs, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Poder Negro--Brazilian Performance, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Epistrophe, undated (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Fire!, undated (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Force!, undated (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - General Hag's Skeezag, undated (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Home on the Range, undated (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Images of Struggle and Revolution, undated (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Incredible Rocky or Black Power, undated (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Jack Pot Melting: A Commercial, undated (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Knee Cult Surveillance, undated (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Langston Hughes 90th Birthday Celebration Script, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - The Life and Life of Bumpy Johnson, 1972-1993
      - Budget, undated (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - Drafts, 1987; (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 38-39)
      - Notebooks, 1991
        - One and Two, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 40)
        - Three and Four, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 41)
        - Five, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 42)
      - Photos, undated (Box 26, Folder 43)
      - Printed Material, 1972-1991 (Box 26, Folder 44)
        - Clippings and Reviews, 1972-1991 (Box 26, Folder 45)
        - Performance Material, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Lyrics and Music, undated (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Madheart: A Morality Play, undated (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Marvin X, undated (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Meeting Lillie, 1988-2003 (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Money, 1982
      - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Photos, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Printed Material, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Score, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - The Most Dangerous Man in America, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - The Motion of History, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Nat Turner, 2004
      - Drafts, 2004 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Stage Blocking, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - New Arkestra, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - The New Voice, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Othello, Jr., undated (Box 27, Folder 12)